sparked.com 2013-11-29

# Sparked - Customer Teams Platform | Privacy Policy

You are here: [Home](http://hello.sparked.com/ "Sparked") / Privacy Policy

_**————————————————————-**_ _ **———————————————-**_ **  
**The Extraordinaries, Inc. Privacy Policy****  
_**————————————————————-**_ _ **———————————————-**_  
October 20, 2009

The Extraordinaries, Inc. (“The Extraordinaries”) provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information we receive from users of [www.sparked.com](http://www.sparked.com/ "www.sparked.com") (the “Site”) and our related interactive microvolunteering and crowd sourcing platform (including but not limited to our iPhone and iPod Touch application) (the “Platform”) and when you use a hosted application provided by an Extraordinaries Subscriber (defined below) via our Platform (“Hosted Application”) (any and all of the foregoing, the “Services”). This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through the Services (including that which we may collect on your behalf) when you use the Services.

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time.  We will notify you of any material changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on the Site.  You are advised to consult this policy regularly for any changes.

As used in this policy, the terms “using” and “processing” information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

Information Collection and Use

Personally Identifiable Information.

o    In the course of using the Services (including a Hosted Application), we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you and administer your account (“Personal Information”).  Personal Information includes, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, credit card or other billing information, email address and home and business postal addresses.  We use your Personal Information mainly to provide the Services and administer your inquiries.

o    We also collect the other information that you provide as part of registration and the administration and personalization of your profile webpage (e.g., without limitation, zip code (on its own) and individual preferences) (“Non-Identifying Information”).

o    We use your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your Non-Identifying Information) mainly to provide the Services, complete your transactions, and administer your inquiries.

o    Certain Non-Identifying Information would be considered a part of your Personal Information if it were combined with other identifiers (for example, combining your zip code with your street address) in a way that enables you to be identified.  But the same pieces of information are considered Non-Identifying Information when they are taken alone or combined only with other non-identifying information (for example, your viewing preferences).  We may combine your Personal Information with Non-Identifying Information and aggregate it with information collected from other Extraordinaries users to attempt to provide you with a better experience, to improve the quality and value of the Services and to analyze and understand how our Site and Services are used. We may also use the combined information without aggregating it to serve you specifically, for instance to deliver a product to you according to your preferences or restrictions.

o    We also use your Personal Information to contact you with The Extraordinaries newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you.  If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or update your “user preferences” information. (See “Changing or Deleting Information,” below.)

o    Extraordinaries does not sell, rent, lease or disclose your Personal Information. Except as described in this Privacy Policy, your Personal Information will be used only by Extraordinaries and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates, and your Personal Information will not be disclosed to any other third party without your consent.

o    Extraordinaries will store personal data until account deletion is requested. At that point, personal data will be scheudled for deletion. Some data may not be deleteable, such as activity listings in public activity feeds. These feeds contain a minimum of personal data (First name and Last Initial only).

Log Data.  When you use the Services, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website or online service (“Log Data”).  This Log Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Site, pages of our Site that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Site, access times and dates, and other statistics.  We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Site and the Services and for the Site’s technical administration, to increase our Site’s functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor it to our visitors’ needs.  For example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit the Site again, it will recognize you and serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests.  We also use this information to verify that visitors to the Site meet the criteria required to process their requests.

Cookies

Like many websites, we use “cookies” to collect information.  A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes.  We use cookies for two purposes.  First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Site.  Second, we utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Site, to better understand how you interact with the Site and to monitor aggregate usage by Extraordinaries users and web traffic routing on the Site.  Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Site and Services and then close your browser.  Third party advertisers on the Site or Services may also place or read cookies on your browser.  You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit.  If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of the Services.

Information Collected on Behalf of and Shared with Our Users

As used in this Privacy Policy, “Usage Data” means the tracking and usage data generated by Volunteer Users and collected by The Extraordinaries in connection with the Services, including an Volunteer User’s personally identifiable information; and “Volunteer User” means a visitor to or user of a  Hosted Application.

Hosted Applications.

o    When you deploy a Hosted Application, as your agent and on your behalf we may collect Usage Data provided by Volunteer Users of a Hosted Application which will contain the personally identifiable information of such Volunteer User.

o    If you are an Volunteer User of  a Hosted Application, the terms of this Privacy Policy govern the use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information in our capacity as a third party service provider to the entity or individual on whose behalf The Extraordinaries collected such information (“Extraordinaries Subscriber”).  We will share this information with the relevant Extraordinaries Subscriber pursuant to your request to interact, follow and/or participate in the Extraordinaries Subscriber’s service via its Hosted Application.

Emailing Via an Extraordinaries  Account  
As part of the Services, registered users may communicate with registered and non-registered users through use of their accounts.  Where a registered user has selected the option of adding one or more email addresses to an online form, the message they create in the corresponding template will be sent from The Extraordinaries to those email addresses on their behalf.

Phishing  
Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to Extraordinaries.  Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a top priority.  We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, your account ID, login password, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication.  For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission’s website.

Information Sharing and Disclosure

Extraordinaries Users.  In addition to your username, we will display your Personal Information in your profile page and elsewhere on the Site or via the Services according to the preferences you set in your account. In addition, any comments or submissions that you post to the Site or via Services may be publicly available. For example, if you are using the social community networking features of our Services the information you publish will be viewable by other users.  Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want other users to know about you.  We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information and we encourage Extraordinaries users to think carefully about what information about themselves they disclose in their comments or submissions.

Volunteer User Information. Depending on the functionality chosen by an Extraordinaries Subscriber,  we may share Volunteer User information with that party.

Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information.   We may share aggregated information that includes your Personal Information, Non-Identifying Information and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis and demographic profiling and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services.

Service Providers.  We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Services, to provide the Services on our behalf, to perform Site-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Site’s features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Site and Services are used.  These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. We may also provide Personal Information to our business partners or other trusted entities for the purpose of providing you with information on goods or services we believe will be of interest to you.  You can, at any time, opt out of receiving such communications.

Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement.  The Extraordinaries will cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law.  We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of  The Extraordinaries or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, any illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

Business Transfers.  The Extraordinaries may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy. The Extraordinaries will notify you before transferring your information to a new entity as part of a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of some or all of its assets if the new entity’s processing of your information will materially differ from that set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Changing or Deleting Your Information

All registered users may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their registration profile by contacting us.  If you completely delete all such information, then your account may become deactivated.  If you would like us to delete your record in our system, please contact us at privacy at beextra dot org with a request that we delete your Personal Information from our database. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request.  We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes.

Security

The Extraordinaries are very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ certain physical, technological, and administrative security measures, but they may not be reasonable or applicable under the circumstances and, in any case, no security measures can be guaranteed to protect your data.

We will make any legally required disclosures of any  breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored “personal data” (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on this Site in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

International Transfer

Your information may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction.  If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, The Extraordinaries transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there.  Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Links to Other Sites

Our Services contains links to other websites.  If you choose to visit an advertiser by “clicking on” a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s website.  The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices.  We do not exercise control over third party websites.  These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you.  Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them.  We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

Our Policy Toward Children

The Site and Services are not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13.   If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at privacy at beextra dot org.  If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

_**————————————————————-**_ _ **———————————————-**_ **  
**Safe Harbor Update, June 28, 2012****  
_**————————————————————-**_ _ **———————————————-**_

The Extraordinaries complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. The Extraordinaries has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view The Extraordinaries’ certification, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/

_**————————————————————-**_ _ **———————————————-**_

Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at **  support@sparked.com**

or at:

The Extraordinaries, Inc.  
155 9th St.  
San Francisco, CA 94103


